counterpath.com 2019-07-01

# Privacy Policy | CounterPath

Last updated: May 18, 2018

CounterPath Corporation (“CounterPath”) is committed to protecting the privacy of customers and users of our website, products and services. This Privacy Policy explains what personal data we collect from you and how we use it. This Privacy Policy pertains to our online collection of data from our web properties and to our collection of data from your use of our products or services. We encourage you to read the full policy below as by using our website, products or services, and submitting any personal information, you consent to the collection and use of this information by CounterPath.

Also, please be aware that our Privacy Policy may change from time to time to evolve with the products and services we offer you and changing technologies. Be sure to check back here periodically for any changes.

CounterPath is sensitive to the private nature of information you provide to us over the Internet. Our privacy practices are designed to maximize your ability to control the use of your personal, private information while at the same time giving you the opportunity to obtain interesting and useful information, products and services.

## Personal Data We Collect

CounterPath collects data to operate effectively and provide you with the best experiences with our products and services. You provide some of this data directly when you purchase one of our products or services, register for a program, or when you contact us for support. We also get some of it by recording how you interact with our services, for example, using technologies like cookies, receiving error reports or usage data from software running on your device, or tracking IP addresses when you visit our website.

Data we collect depends on the products, services and features you use, and can include the following:

**Name and contact data.** We collect your first and last name, email address, postal address, phone number, and other similar contact data.

**Credentials.** We collect passwords and security information used for authentication and account access.

**Demographic data.** We collect data about you such as your country and preferred language.

**Payment data.** We, or our third party service providers, collect data necessary to process your payment if you make purchases, such as your credit card number, CCV number or PayPal account information.

**Usage data.** We collect data about how you and your device interact with our services. This includes data, such as the features you use, items you purchase, and web pages your visit. This also includes data about your device and the network you use to connect to our services, including IP address, device identifiers, regional and language settings. This includes information about the operating systems and other CounterPath software installed on your device. And it includes data about the performance of the products or services and any problems you experience with them.

**Location data.** We collect information about your location in two ways. When you register or purchase a product or service we may request a billing address or country location. We also may derive data from your IP address.

**Content.** We collect content of your files and communications when necessary to provide you with the services you use. For example, if you receive a message using a CounterPath hosted messaging service, we need to collect the content of that message in order to deliver it to your softphone client, display it to you, enable you to reply to it, and store it for you until you choose to delete it. Examples of this data include the content of instant messages, or documents, photos, music or videos you file transfer using CounterPath services.

We also collect the content of messages you send to us, such as feedback and product reviews you write, or questions or information you provide for customer support. When you contact us, such as for customer support, chat sessions with our representatives may be monitored and recorded.

## How We Use Personal Data

CounterPath uses the data we collect to provide you with the services we offer and to improve and personalize your experiences, as well as the products and services CounterPath provides. We also may use the data to communicate with you, including sending you information on security updates, account status notices and product changes or updates. Further details on how we specifically use your data are outlined below:

**Providing and improving our products and services.** We use data to provide and improve the services we offer and perform essential business operations. This includes operating the services, maintaining and improving the performance of the services, including development of new features, research, and providing customer support.

**Communications.** We use the data we collect to deliver and personalize communications with you. For example, we may contact you by email or other means to inform you when a subscription is ending, let you know when updates are available, remind you about items left in your online shopping cart, invite you to participate in a survey, or tell you about new products or services available to you. Additionally, you can choose to sign up for email subscriptions, like our News Subscription list, and choose whether you wish to receive promotional material along with your subscription. We do not sell any information we collect to third parties. With any of our promotional material emails, you will have the option to unsubscribe from future mailings from a link within the email communication. You can also contact CounterPath directly in order to unsubscribe by emailing [marketing@counterpath.com](mailto:marketing@counterpath.com).

**Business operations and compliance.** As a publicly traded company, CounterPath is required to file numerous reports with different administrative bodies. As such, we may provide aggregate statistics about customers, sales and traffic patterns. None of these reports or statistics include personally identifiable information. However, CounterPath reserves the right to use personally identifiable information to investigate and help prevent potentially unlawful activity that threatens either CounterPath or any company affiliated with CounterPath. Moreover, upon the appropriate request of a government agency, law enforcement, court or as otherwise required by law, CounterPath may disclose personally identifiable information.

**Push notification.** To let you know of incoming calls, chats and other messages, our apps use the notification service on your device. For many devices, these services are provided by another company. To tell you who is calling, for example, or to give you the first few words of the new chat, our service has to tell the company providing the notification service so that they can provide the notification to you. The company providing the notification service on your device will use this information in accordance with their own terms and privacy policy. CounterPath is not responsible for the data collected by the company providing the notification service. If you don’t want to use the notification services with our applications, turn it off in the settings found in the application or your device.

## Cookies

CounterPath collects information related to your use of our website using cookies. Cookies are small files containing strings of text stored on your computer. CounterPath may use cookies to authenticate you as a user when you log in, track your session, deliver content specific to your preferences and interests, store the contents of your shopping cart, provide features related to payment and customer service, and provide other functions.

CounterPath retains such information for as long as reasonably required for business purposes or as reasonably required to comply with our legal obligations. If you would like to learn more about your privacy and how we handle cookies, please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://go.counterpath.com/privacy/cookie-policy).

## Corrections/Complaints

CounterPath shall honor email requests sent to [privacy@counterpath.com](mailto:privacy@counterpath.com) from customers to change their account information (i.e., name, address or billing information) or otherwise correct inaccurate information. CounterPath will gladly correct such information and customers are welcome to verify that the appropriate corrections have been made. In addition, if you believe that your personally identifiable information is being mishandled in light of this Privacy Policy, please immediately notify CounterPath by email at [privacy@counterpath.com](mailto:privacy@counterpath.com) so that we can address your concern.

## Security

We take great care and use the latest technologies to ensure the security and safety of all your transactions with CounterPath. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place safeguards to secure the information we collect online. Our servers use encryption technology to protect the transfer of your credit card data to unauthorized parties. When these types of measures are taken, shopping online is safe and secure. We use industry-recognized standards in transaction security to protect the information you provide when you make a purchase at CounterPath.

## Links to Other Sites

This website contains links to other web pages and websites. CounterPath is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. You are encouraged to review the privacy policies of these other websites before registering for any products or services from that website.

## Children

Our website is directed to individuals who are the age of majority or older in their jurisdiction. We do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13. If you believe your child has provided information to this website, please contact using the information provided below.

## General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) for EU Residents

For information on our policies specific to the GDPR, please see: <https://go.counterpath.com/privacy/gdpr>.

## Questions/Concerns

If, after reading our Privacy Policy, you have questions or concerns about any of the statements herein, or would like to correct personal information, you may contact us at:

Attention: Privacy Officer  
CounterPath Corporation  
300-505 Burrard Street  
Vancouver, BC, Canada V7X 1M3  
By e-mail: [privacy@counterpath.com](mailto:privacy@counterpath.com)
